pelco.com 2019-12-06

# Pelco Privacy Policy

Pelco Data privacy statement

1\. Pelco commits to protecting your personal information

Pelco is committed to protecting your privacy and your personal information. We encourage you to read this privacy statement. 

This Privacy Statement informs you of our privacy practices and the way your personal information is collected online and how that information is used by us. Pelco strongly supports the fundamental rights to privacy and data Protection as well as compliance with national and international privacy laws.

   In the legal and ethical principles, "Our Principles of Responsibility “, Pelco commits to maintain confidential any personal information and to strictly limit any disclosure in accordance with local laws. 

2\. To whom this Privacy statement applies

Pelco is a global company, with legal entities, business processes, management structures, and technical systems that cross borders. This Privacy Statement applies to all Pelco -owned websites, domains, services, applications, and products.

3\. How we process your personal information?

Pelco respects the privacy rights and interests of each individual, employee, candidate or customer. Pelco will observe the following principles when processing your personal information: 

  1. Processing your personal information fairly and lawfully. 
  2. Collecting your personal information for specified, legitimate purposes and not processing further in ways incompatible with those purposes. 
  3. Collecting your personal information which is relevant to and not excessive for the purposes for which it is collected and used.  We may render information anonymous when feasible and appropriate, depending on the nature of the data and the risks associated with the intended uses. 
  4. Maintaining your personal information accurate, and where necessary, kept up-to-date. We will take reasonable steps to rectify or delete data that is inaccurate or incomplete. 
  5. Keeping your personal information only as long as it is necessary for the purposes for which it was collected and processed. 
  6. Processing your personal information in accordance with the individual’s legal rights. 
  7. Taking appropriate technical, physical, and organizational measures to prevent unauthorized access, unlawful processing, and unauthorized or accidental loss, destruction, or damage to personal information. 
  8. Processing your personal information based on the following legal basis: 

  * You have unambiguously given your consent; or 
  * The processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract; or 
  * The processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which Pelco is subject; or 
  * The processing is necessary in order to protect the vital interests of the data subject; or 
  * The processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the controller or in a third party to whom the data is disclosed; or 
  * The processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by Pelco or by the third party or parties to whom the data is disclosed, except where such interests are overridden by the interests for fundamental rights and freedoms of the data subject. 

4\. Why we collect your personal information?

Our primary goals in collecting information are to provide our customers and other users with superior service and a smooth, efficient and personalized experience while using our site or services. For example, if you purchase products or request information on the sites, we use your personal information to fill your order or provide the requested information. 

Pelco may collect personal Information from you to complete various transactions, such as: 

  * Product or service orders, activations and registrations 
  * Profile creation 
  * Information requests 
  * Marketing or support subscriptions 
  * Contest entries or survey participation
  * Notifications of firmware updates

5\. What information is collected?

Pelco collects and uses your personal information to better serve you and personalize your experience and interaction. Such collection is done with appropriate notice and consent, along with required filings with data protection authorities, where applicable. 

Personal information (or personal data) means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person ('data subject'); an identifiable person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identification number or to one or more factors specific to his physical, physiological, mental, economic, cultural or social identity. 

This privacy statement does not cover personal information rendered anonymous or where pseudonyms are used. Data is rendered anonymous if individual persons are no longer identifiable or are identifiable only with a disproportionately large expense in time, cost, or labor. The use of pseudonyms involves the replacement of names or other identifiers with substitutes, so that identification of individual persons is either impossible or at least rendered considerably more difficult. If data rendered anonymous becomes no longer anonymous (i.e., individual persons are again identifiable), or if pseudonyms are used and the pseudonyms allow identification of individual persons, then this privacy statement will again apply. 

It is always up to you whether to disclose personal information to us, although if you elect not to do so, we reserve the right not to register you as a user or provide you with any products or services. 

The types of personal information we collect from you may include: 

  * Your name, company, email address, phone number, billing address and shipping address 
  * Customer type, job function, job title, purchasing authority, purchasing timeframe and others
  * Product and service preferences, contact preferences, educational and employment background, and job interest data
  * Credit card information (where applicable) 
  * IP address (see chapter on cookies) 

**How We Use Your Information  **

We gather and use information in a number of ways, including the following: 

Browsing and Searching: We collect certain personal Information when you visit the sites or click on the various links for products and services. We collect this information to improve your web user experience for your next visits (ex: country selection), help run the sites more efficiently, to gather broad demographic information, to monitor the level of activity on the sites, and to evaluate the effectiveness of our advertising. (See chapter 7 about cookies) 

Ordering: We collect Personal Information when you purchase products and services. We collect this information to deliver your order, to obtain payment, and to communicate with you about the status of your order. 

Technical support: We may collect certain information when you request technical support for Pelco products. This information is necessary to identify your systems, understand the configuration of the products, diagnose your questions, and provide solutions. 

Online surveys and polling: We collect Personal Information from customers who volunteer to complete surveys or participate in polls. We use this information to improve our products and services. 

Promotional activities: We collect Personal Information from you when you enter a promotional program or activity. We use this information to administer the program or activity, to send you promotional e-mails, notify winners, and make the winners' list publicly available pursuant to applicable regulations and laws.

Newsletters and promotional e-mails: We collect Personal Information when you ask to receive newsletters, promotional e-mails, and other information. We use this information to provide you the information you request. 

Contact information: If you contact us, we keep a record of your correspondence or comments, including Personal Information, in a file specific to you. We use this information to help us provide you better service in the event you contact us again. 

We may keep your information for a reasonable period for the purposes set out above. 

How do we use your information for marketing? 

To inform you, by letter, fax, phone, SMS and email about promotions, news and new products that we think may be of interest to you.  By providing us with your information you consent to being contacted by these methods for these purposes. **If you do not wish to receive marketing information** from us you can manage communication preferences at any time by [clicking here](http://info.pelco.com/PreferenceCenter) and check the box to unsubscribe from all communications. 

6\. What we do with your personal data

If you do provide personal information to us, either directly or through a reseller or other business partner, we will: 

Not sell or rent it to a third party without your permission — although unless you opt–in , we may use your contact information to provide you with information we believe you need to know or may find useful, such as (for example) news about our services and products and modifications to the Terms of Service;

Take commercially reasonable precautions to protect the information from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction; 

Not use or disclose the information except: 

  * As necessary to provide services or products you have ordered, such as (for example) by providing it to a carrier to deliver products you have ordered;

  * In other ways described in this privacy policy or to which you have otherwise consented;  
 
  * In the aggregate with other information in such a way so that your identity cannot reasonably be determined (for example, statistical compilations);  
 
  * As required by law, for example, in response to a subpoena or search warrant;

  * To outside auditors who have agreed to keep the information confidential; 

  * As necessary to enforce the Terms of Service;

  * As necessary to protect the rights, safety, or property of Pelco, its users, or others; this may include (for example) exchanging information with other organizations for fraud protection and/or risk reduction. 

7\. Cookies

A cookie is a piece of information in the form of a very small text file that is placed on an internet user's hard drive. It is generated by a web page server, which is basically the computer that operates a web site. The information the cookie contains is set by the server and it can be used by that server whenever the user visits the site. A cookie can be thought of as an internet user's identification card, which tell a web site when the user has returned.   
_(Source:  _[ _www.AboutCookies.org_](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) _)_

Using cookies enables us to provide you with certain features and provides us with information regarding website visits. We may use cookies also to allow us to make the sites more user friendly. Most browsers automatically accept cookies but you do not have to accept them. You can usually change your browser to prevent acceptance and you should still be able to enjoy most of the features on the sites. 

If you want to delete any cookies that are already on your computer or to stop cookies being accepted in the future you should refer to your browser manufacturer's instructions by clicking "Help" in your browser menu. More information is available at [www.AboutCookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/). 

Third party cookies for analytics purpose 

In order to provide our visitors with a better experience, we measure the number of page views, the number of visits, the different actions performed by visitors on our site, the geo-location of our visitors and the number of times visitors return to our site. For this purpose, we use web analytics software tools: Google Analytics, Google Advertising, Marketo Munchkin Cookie, Facebook Tracking Pixel, and LinkedIn Insight Tag.

**Google Analytics information**

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. 

In case IP-anonymization is activated on this website, your IP address will be truncated within the area of Member States of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases the whole IP address will be first transferred to a Google server in the USA and truncated there. The IP-anonymization is active on this website. 

Google will use this information on behalf of the operator of this website for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing them other services relating to website activity and internet usage. 

The IP-address that your browser conveys within the scope of Google Analytics will not be associated with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. You can also opt-out from being tracked by Google Analytics with effect for the future by downloading and installing Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on for your current web browser: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>

**Google Advertising Cookies**

Google uses cookies to help serve the ads it displays on the websites of its partners, such as websites displaying Google ads or participating in Google certified ad networks. When users visit a Google partner's website, a cookie may be dropped on that end user's browser.  

DoubleClick DART cookies: We also may use DART cookies for ad serving through Google’s DoubleClick, which places a cookie on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site using DoubleClick advertising (including some Google AdSense advertisements). This cookie is used to serve ads specific to you and your interests (”interest based targeting”). The ads served will be targeted based on your previous browsing history (For example, if you have been viewing sites about visiting Las Vegas, you may see Las Vegas hotel advertisements when viewing a non-related site, such as on a site about hockey). DART uses “non personally identifiable information”. It does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers. You can opt-out of this ad serving on all sites using this advertising by visiting <http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx>

You can choose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

Deleting cookies does not mean you are permanently opted out of any advertising program. Unless you have settings that disallow cookies, the next time you visit a site running the advertisements, a new cookie will be added.

**Marketo Munchkin Cookie**

We use third party marketing software from a company called Marketo to send our emails. We use cookies as part of tracking, so we have information on email open rates and click through rates. We also track activity on the website. For example, visitors can download marketing white papers from the site and we use Marketo cookies to see who does this and if they then visit other parts of our website. For more information on Marketo’s privacy and cookie policy, please visit Marketo privacy policy: <http://www.marketo.com/trust/legal/privacy>

How does it work? 

  * We embed a Munchkin Javascript snippet on your sites. When visitors come to a site, we place a cookie in the visitor’s web browser (if there wasn’t already one) and send messages to our servers about that visitor’s web activity 
  * This behavior is very functional, very similar to other web tracking scripts such as Google Analytics 
  * Our cookie is a 1st party cookie, and only visible for us. 

What does Munchkin Capture? 

When on a page, Munchkin automatically gathers the following information: 

  * Page Visits 
  * Link Clicks 
  * IP Address 
  * Referrer 
  * Our cookie ID 

**Facebook Tracking Pixel**

We use the “visitor action pixels” from Facebook Inc. This allows user behavior to be tracked after they have been redirected to the provider’s website by clicking on a Facebook ad. This enables us to measure the effectiveness of Facebook ads for statistical and market research purposes. The data collected in this way is anonymous to us, i.e. we do not see the personal data of individual users. However, this data is stored and processed by Facebook, which is why we are informing you, based on our knowledge of the situation. Facebook may link this information to your Facebook account and use it for its own promotional purposes, in accordance with Facebook’s Data Usage Policy https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/. You can allow Facebook and its partners to place ads on and off Facebook. A cookie may also be stored on your computer for these purposes.

You can object to the collection of your data by Facebook pixel, or to the use of your data for the purpose of displaying Facebook ads by contacting the following address: https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads.

Facebook is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement and thus guarantees compliance with European data protection legislation ([https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active)).

**LinkedIn Insights Tag**

The LinkedIn Insight Tag is a piece of lightweight JavaScript code that we have added to our websites to enable in-depth campaign reporting and to help us unlock valuable insights about our website visitors. We use the LinkedIn Insight Tag to track conversions, retarget website visitors, and unlock additional insights about members interacting with our LinkedIn adverts.

The LinkedIn Insight Tag enables the collection of metadata such as IP address information, timestamp, and events such as page views. All data is encrypted. The LinkedIn browser cookie is stored in a visitor's browser until they delete the cookie or the cookie expires (there’s a rolling six-month expiration from the last time the visitor’s browser loaded the Insight Tag).

You can opt out of cookies from LinkedIn on your [LinkedIn settings page](https://www.linkedin.com/settings/?trk=) and recommend you read their [Cookie Policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy) for more information.

8\. How we protect your information

Pelco and its subsidiaries are committed to taking appropriate technical, physical, and organizational measures to protect its Employees and Customers Personal Data against unauthorized access, unlawful processing, accidental loss or damage, and unauthorized destruction. 

We offer the use of a secure server to enable you to place orders or access your account information.  This encrypts your information before it is sent to us. We also take appropriate measures to ensure that the information disclosed to us is kept secure, accurate and up to date and kept only for so long as is necessary for the purposes for which it is used. 

We limit access to our internal systems that hold Personal Data to a selected group of authorized users who are given access to such systems through the use of a unique identifier and password. Access to Personal Data is limited to and provided to individuals for the purpose of performing their job duties. 

Our Third Party Access Policy defines the rules regarding the access types to be granted to the third parties, according to their needs and the security level to be ensured. This policy is applicable to all third parties requiring access to systems, applications, network devices and services and aims at limiting the risks of unauthorized access to Pelco Information systems by ensuring limited accesses to the specific needs. 

However, we cannot guarantee the security of any data you provide to us and you accept the inherent risks of on-line correspondence and purchases over the internet. Any purchases made by you via the Sites are subject to the terms and conditions contained on the Sites. 

9\. Links to third-party websites

Pelco sites or services may provide links to third-party applications, products, services, or websites for your convenience and information. If you access those links, you will leave the Pelco site. Pelco does not control those third-party sites or their privacy practices, which may differ from Pelco’s practices. We do not endorse or make any representations about third-party sites. The personal information you choose to provide to or that is collected by these third parties is not covered by the Pelco Privacy Statement. We encourage you to review the privacy policy of any site you interact with before allowing the collection and use of your personal information. 

We may also provide social media links that enable you to share information with your social networks and to interact with Pelco on various social media sites. Your use of these links may result in the collection or sharing of information about you, depending on the feature. We encourage you to review the privacy policies and settings on the social media sites with which you interact to make sure you understand the information that may be collected, used, and shared by those sites. 

If you post, comment, indicate interest, or share personal information, including photographs, to any public forum, social network, blog, or other such forum, please be aware that any personal information you submit can be read, viewed, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to contact you, send you unsolicited messages, or for purposes that neither you nor Pelco have control over Pelco is not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these forums. 

10\. Your rights to access and erasure

Your rights under GDPR, CASL and CalOPPA include, the right to access a copy of your Personal Information, the right to request the correction or the update of any inaccurate Personal Information and the right to object to the processing of your Personal Information under the conditions set out in applicable law.

You also have the right to request the erasure of your Personal Information and, where you have consented to the processing of your Personal Information, you have the right to withdraw such consent at any time (without this withdrawal affecting the lawfulness of the processing prior to such withdrawal). In addition, you also have the right to data portability in certain cases. This is the right to request the return of the Personal Information you have provided to us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and to request the transmission of such Personal Information to a third party, without hindrance from us and subject to your own confidentiality obligations.

If you wish to exercise any of the above rights please contact us using the information below.

   Pelco Privacy

625 W Alluvial Ave

Fresno, Ca, 93711

559-292-1981

800-289-9100  

If you are not satisfied with how we process your Personal Information, you may contact us using any of the communication means listed above or alternatively you may file a complaint with the competent supervisory authority, in addition to your rights outlined above.

11\. Change in this privacy statement

Pelco reserves the right to modify this privacy statement as needed, for example, to comply with changes in laws, regulations, Pelco practices and procedures, or requirements imposed by data protection authorities. 

In this case, Pelco will inform Pelco candidates, Customers and other persons of any material changes in this privacy statement. Pelco will post all changes on relevant internal and external websites. 

This statement and the policies referred herein are not intended to and do not create any contractual or other legal rights. 

Last update:  22 May 2019
